Brown, A.W. mss., 1915-1944 LMC 2342
Lilly Library
Brown, A.W. mss.
1915-1944
Lilly Library
Brown, Arthur William, 1881-1966
LMC 2342
10 Boxes
The Brown, A.W. mss. consists of family photos, correspondence, and original drawings, ca. 1915-1944, by artist and magazine illustrator Arthur William Brown.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
The Brown, A.W. mss. Consists of family photos, correspondence, and drawings by Canadian artist and illustrator Arthur William Brown (1881-1966). During the 1890s, Brown was a student of John Gordon at the Hamilton Art School, and later went on to work as a chalk plate artist at the Hamilton Spectator. Eventually, he would move to New York City and become an illustrator for the Saturday Evening Post. Brown became known for his book illustrations and covers for American fiction by authors such as F.Scott Fitzgerald and Sinclair Lewis. He also produced World War I posters.
The collection includes several of his original drawings for Scribner's and the Saturday Evening Post. The last box also contains more familial memorabilia.
Scope and Content Note
The Brown, A.W. mss. consists of family photos, correspondence, and original drawings, ca. 1915-1944, by artist and magazine illustrator Arthur William Brown. These items were collected by or sent to Willis Pyle, an illustrator whose collections also reside at the Lilly Library.
Related Materials
See Pyle, W. mss., also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 2001
Art; Brown, Arthur William, 1881-1966
- #1-5 (Box 2)
  - Every Saturday Night Ladies Home Journal, February 1943; Black and white wash, 18 X 26 3/4" vignette, signed lower right. (Box 2)
  - Claudia and David Redbook, December 1939; Black and blue wash, 18 X 13", signed lower left. (Box 2)
  - Red Letter Day Woman's Home Companion, October 1944; Black, yellow, and green watercolor, 15 X 14 1/4", signed lower left. (Box 2)
  - Stranger Than Truth Redbook, June 1940; Black and blue wash, 14 X 20" vignette, signed lower left. (Stained) (Box 2)
  - She's the Boss Ladies Home Journal, May 1945; Black and white wash, 18 X 23" vignette, signed lower right. (Box 2)
- #6-10 (Box 3)
  - Mr. Tutt, girl, and man.Saturday Evening Post, 1941; Black and white wolff pencil and wash, 19 X 13", signed upper right. (Box 3)
  - Mr. Tutt, Should I Apologize? Saturday Evening Post, 3 black and white spots, wash, 15 X 22", signed middle left. (Box 3)
  - Mr. Tutt and young man. Saturday Evening Post, 1927; Wolff pencil and wash, 17 X 22" vignette, signed lower left. (Box 3)
  - Mr. Tutt and middle-aged man. Saturday Evening Post, 1927; Wolff pencil and wash, 16 X 19" vignette, signed lower left. (Box 3)
  - Mr. Tutt and middle-aged man and widow. Saturday Evening Post, 1944; Black and white wash, green and yellow watercolor, 15 X 18 1/2" vignette, signed lower left. (Box 3)
- #11-[20] (Box 4)
  - Mr. Tutt dancing. Saturday Evening Post, 1927; Black and white wolff pencil and wash, 17 X 21 1/2" vignette, signed lower right. (Box 4)
  - Two officers in conversation., Black and white wash, 12 X 14", signed lower left. (Box 4)
  - Woman unpacking trunk. Saturday Evening Post, Black and white wash, 11 X 19", signed lower right. (Box 4)
  - Marriage of Claudia Redbook, Red and black wash, 15 X 21", signed lower left. (Box 4)
  - Spun Sunshine Woman's Home Companion, October 1919; Red and black wash, 12 X 17 1/2", signed lower left. (Box 4)
  - Social scene, young woman and two men., Wolff pencil and wash, 14 X 16 1/2", corner broken lower right. (Box 4)
  - Couple in office. Saturday Evening Post, 1931; Wolff pencil and wash, 16 X 20" vignette, signed lower right. (Box 4)
  - Three young women. Saturday Evening Post, 1929; Wolff pencil and wash, 15 1/2 X 21" vignette, signed lower right. (Box 4)
  - Woman with phone and middle-aged man. Saturday Evening Post, 1924; Wolff pencil and wash, 16 X 18" vignette, signed lower right. (Box 4)
- #21-30 (Box 5)
  - Man and young woman in office. Saturday Evening Post, 1923; Wolff pencil, 15 X 20", signed lower right. (Box 5)
  - Man and blond woman in office. Saturday Evening Post, 1927; Wolff pencil and wash, 18 X 14" vignette, signed lower right. (Box 5)
  - Three women in conversation. Liberty Magazine, 1924; Wolff pencil and wash, 17 X 17" vignette, signed lower right. (corner broken upper left) (Box 5)
  - Young couple., Wolff pencil and wash, 12 X 16" vignette, signed lower left. (Box 5)
  - Two young women., 1923; Wolff pencil and wash, 16 X 19 1/2" vignette, signed lower left. (cracked, needs repair) (Box 5)
  - Young man and older man. Saturday Evening Post, 1925; Wolff pencil and wash, 15 X 21" vignette, signed lower left. (Box 5)
  - Couple on garden bench. Saturday Evening Post, 1923; Wolff pencil and wash, 17 X 16" vignette, signed lower left. (cracked, needs repair) (Box 5)
- #[31]-40 (Box 6)
  - Couple by lake. Saturday Evening Post, Wolff pencil and wash, 15 X 15" vignette, signed lower left. (Box 6)
  - Man reading/bored young woman. Saturday Evening Post, 1927; Wolff pencil and wash, 15 X 12" vignette, signed lower left. (Box 6)
  - Two spiffy young men. Saturday Evening Post, Wolff pencil and wash, 12 X 10 1/2" vignette, signed lower right. (Box 6)
  - Young couple in conversation. Saturday Evening Post, Wolff pencil and wash, 12 X 10" vignette, not signed. (Box 6)
  - Young couple in quarrel. Saturday Evening Post, 1922; Wolff pencil and wash, 17 X 16" vignette, signed lower right. (Box 6)
  - Arguing a baseball call. Saturday Evening Post, Wolff pencil and wash, 9 X 9 1/2" vignette, signed lower left. (Box 6)
- #41-49 (Box 7)
  - Tourist Party Saturday Evening Post, 1930; Wolff pencil and wash, 18 X 25", signed lower right. (needs repair) (Box 7)
  - Song for a Hero officer and girl in embrace., April 1944; Wolff pencil and wash, 10 X 9" vignette, not signed. (Box 7)
  - Anguished young man., 1939; Wolff pencil and wash, 21 X 9 1/2" vignette, signed twice lower left. (Box 7)
  - Altercation in cellar. Saturday Evening Post, 1941; Wolff pencil and wash, 21 X 11 1/2", signed twice lower left. (Box 7)
  - Girl in swim suit, surfing.Saturday Evening Post, Wolff pencil and wash, 18 X 9 1/2", signed twice lower left. (Box 7)
  - Three panels of golfers in costume. Saturday Evening Post, Wolff pencil and wash, 4 X 10 1/2", 4 X 10 1/2", 6 X 10 1/2", not signed. (Box 7)
  - Young man on farm. Saturday Evening Post, Wolff pencil and wash, 11 X 9". (Box 7)
  - There he is... Scribner's, Wolff pencil and wash, 12 1/2 X 8 3/4", signed lower right. (Box 7)
- #50-60 (Box 8)
  - YMCA Poster circa WWI, Watercolor with lettering, 13 X 10 1/4", signed lower left. (Box 8)
  - Quartet on train. McClure's, 1916; Wolff pencil and wash, 9 1/2 X 10 3/4", signed lower right. (Box 8)
  - Pensive seamstress. Saturday Evening Post, 1924; Wolff pencil and wash, 17 X 12 1/2", signed lower right. (Box 8)
  - Young and older woman. Saturday Evening Post, 1922; Wolff pencil and wash, 15 X 17" vignette, signed lower left. (Box 8)
  - Mother and daughter. Saturday Evening Post, 1927; Wolff pencil and wash, 16 X 20", signed lower right. (Box 8)
  - Red Cross Workers WWI era, Red and black wash, 8 X 11 3/4", signed lower right. (Box 8)
  - Seventeen by Booth Tarkington, Black and white wolff pencil and wash, 9 3/4 X 7", signed lower right. (Box 8)
  - Family conversation in parlor., 1908; Brush and ink, 7 1/2 X 12 1/2", signed lower right. (Box 8)
  - Carrying wash tub on head. Metropolitan Magazine, February 1915 (Box 8)
- #[61]-72 (Box 9)
  - Two boys and three girls. Saturday Evening Post, Wolff pencil and watercolor wash, 13 X 18 3/4", signed lower right. (corner broken) (Box 9)
  - Magnificent Ambersons Saturday Evening Post, Wolff pencil and watercolor wash, 12 X 17", signed lower right. (Box 9)
  - Angry boys and young woman. Saturday Evening Post, Wolff pencil and watercolor wash, 12 X 17 1/2", signed lower left. (Box 9)
  - Two men in formal dress. Saturday Evening Post, Wolff pencil and watercolor wash, 14 X 10 1/2", signed lower right. (Box 9)
  - Man counting money. Scribner's, 1917; 12 X 12", signed lower right. (Box 9)
  - Woman and two men. Scribner's, Wolff pencil and watercolor wash, 13 X 13", signed lower right. (Box 9)
  - Young woman and soldier. Scribner's, Wolff pencil and watercolor wash, 9 1/2 X 12", signed lower right. (Box 9)
  - Young man, three women.Scribner's, 1919; Wolff pencil and watercolor wash, 11 X 15", signed lower right. (Box 9)
  - Lawyer Tutt and secretary. Scribner's, 1922; Wolff pencil and watercolor wash, 13 X 19", signed lower right. (Box 9)
- Painting (Box 10)
- Appraisal of collection sent to Willis Pyle, 2002 (Box 1)
- Photos of Arthur William Brown and family, 1884-1908 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1938-1940 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes signed letter from J. Edgar Hoover
- Check from Brown's estate to Willis Pyle, 1967 (Box 1)